MARK LAWRENCE

+64 21 071 7247

markl.nz@hotmail.com

http://markl.nz 🄏

http://github.com/marklnz 🕠

http://linkedin.com/in/marklnz in

SENIOR DEVELOPER DEVELOPMENT TEAM LEAD

I'm a full stack web developer and architect with over 18 years of experience in the IT industry.

I've worked for a wide range of organizations and have experience and technical knowledge of a wide range of tools and techniques used in software development.

I've worked on projects ranging from small projects to multi-million dollar programs of work, in a variety of business sectors.

SKILLS

C# AND .Net: C#, .Net Core CLR, ASP.Net, ASP.Net 5, ASP.Net MVC, Entity Framework, Web API, WCF, ASP.Net Web Services, Windows Forms, WPF, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, MS Test, NUnit, XUnit.

WEB DEVELOPMENT: HTML, CSS, JSON, jQuery, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bootstrap, Responsive Web Development, Node.js, Angular.js.

DATA STORAGE/DATA ACCESS: Microsoft SQL Server, SQL, XML, ER Data Modelling.

DEV OPS: Team Foundation Server, Visual Studio Online, Visual Studio 2015 Team Build, Octopus Deploy, GitHub, Git, Continuous Integration, Continuous Deployment, Automated testing

EXPERIENCE

EYEDE SOLUTIONS, Lower Hutt, NZ

Development Team Lead, Jan 2013 – present Team lead, architect and software engineer.

- Responsible for leading in-house software development team, working predominantly with Microsoft technologies on complex web based applications.
- Oversee and collaborate with the other senior developers in developing Eyede's next generation web application architecture using Angular, TypeScript, JavaScript, HTML 5 and CSS 3.
- Assisted in building developer tooling for the next generation web architecture with Node.js, Gulp, Bower and Karma.
- Full stack software developer and architect.
- Managed Eyede's internal TFS server deployment, and developed the DevOps processes and procedures, using TFS, Team Build and Octopus Deploy
- Migrated Eyede's internal TFS based DevOps tooling to Visual Studio Online, with Git for version control, using Team Build 2015 for build.
- Developed mobile app prototypes using Xamarin's cross platform mobile development tools, as well as the Cordova app development framework.

OPTIMATION LIMITED, Wellington, NZ

Solutions Architect, Jul 2007 – Jan 2013 Senior member of Optimation's C# development team.

- Built Optimation's reusable .net software architecture and reference implementation.
- Served as technical lead and architect on .net projects for Optimation.
- Administered and managed Optimation's Team Foundation Server environment, including process customization and end user training.
- Developed solutions, and effort estimates in presales and contract negotiation situations.
- Performed technical architecture and delivery reviews for a number of customers.

EDS NEW ZEALAND, Wellington, NZ

Senior Developer/Architect, Apr 198 – Jul 2007 Architect, senior developer and project team lead.

 Served as Applications Architect for an account with a major New Zealand government client.
 Was responsible for overall application design on a range of applications, covering technologies

SKILLS

METHODOLOGIES: Scrum, CMMI, MSF

ARCHITECTURE: TOGAF, SOA, Solution Architecture, Integration Technologies.

EDUCATION

Victoria University of Wellington, New Zealand
Bachelor of Science - 1993

REFERENCES

References available on request

- ranging from VB6 through to .net 3.0, in a Service Oriented Architecture environment.
- Contributed to numerous pre-sales efforts, in both New Zealand and throughout the Asia Pacific region.
- Worked with other members of the architecture team, as well as with customer representatives, in defining and evolving an Enterprise Application Architecture for a major New Zealand government client.
- Served as EDS New Zealand's Team Foundation Server expert. Responsibilities ranged from general TFS administration through to customization of tools and processes, as well as user support.
- Composed EDS' global C# coding standards document, as well as acting as reviewer for the global VB.Net coding standards.
- Lead designer and developer on an internal project to build a "request for service" portal, later adopted by EDS sites and customers across the Asia Pacific region.
- Lead developer on a multi-year document imaging and data capture project for another major New Zealand government department.
- Aided in establishing a graduate recruitment program, through conducting interviews of applicants and mentoring successful candidates.

QUEENSLAND RAIL, Brisbane, Australia

Analyst/Programmer, May 1997 – Mar 1998 Senior software developer

- Initially joined to work on mainframe projects using COBOL and DB2.
- Worked on a range of Windows-based and client/server software projects, using Visual Basic and a 4GL programming language.
- Provided second level helpdesk support for users writing macros for Microsoft Office applications

EDS NEW ZEALAND. Wellington, NZ

Analyst/Programmer, Jul 1994 – Feb 1997

- Joined EDS as a graduate mainframe programmer.
- Worked as part of the team supporting one of EDS' major banking clients.
- Developed enhancements and new functionality using CICS COBOL and Assembler language